Dany Majard | Data Scientist

Globally Mobile - France

☐ +33 7 69 80 40 65 • ☑ dany@ledata.science • ③ leData.science

Driven and passionate scientist with commercial sense, initiative, outstanding public speaking skills and a knack for challenges.

Projects

Blockchain // Network Analysis

Google

Cryptocurrencies, graph database, google BigQuery, SQL

June 2018-

Joint work with Allen Day, science Advocate @Google. Analysis of the Bitcoin and Ethereum ledger to improve transparency and raise quantitative knowledge on the cryptocurrencies landscape and smart contracts dynamics.

AdTracking // Fraud Detection

Kaggle Competition

Time Series, feature engineering, AWS cloud computing

Mar-Apr2018

Leaderboard: Top 15%. Constituted a team of ML students to tackle this cyber fraud challenge. Developed a feature engineering crawler to automatically find independent sets of features for ensembling (cf github).

Corporacion Favorita tores // Forecasting

Kaggle Competition

Time series, feature engineering, clustering (python, pandas, sklearn)

Jan 2018

Top 10 Kernel - Using 5 years of sales data across 52 stores of the ecuadorian chain, the goal was to predict sales for optimal stocking. I used unsupervised machine learning to create a cluster feature for a gradient boosting regressor.

Blight in Detroit // Binary Classification

Capstone Project

Geolocation, NLP, webscraping (python, pandas, sklearn)

Nov 2017

Using blight violation tickets and parcel data from Detroit Open Data to predict blight, which is a major problem the city is facing. Extensive EDA and cleaning was needed for models to make factual sense and prevent harmful bias.

Experience

Vocational....

London, UK

Close Brothers (merchant banking) Data Scientist (Client facing)

Aug 2018

- o Provided data science expertise as a service for a client of the bank.
- o Produced extensive documentation of data cleaning and exploratory analysis.
- o Delivered predictive models for 60 days cancellation reducing overhead costs for background checks by up to 30%
- o Delivered predictive models for propensity to take financing, increasing both the bank and the client's yearly earnings.

Career transition to Data science

Paris, Singapore

Professional Development

July 2017-July 2018

- o University of Washington // "Data Science at Scale" Specialization
 - R, Python, SQL, NoSQL, Distributive processing (Pig on Hadoop), Machine Learning, Vizualization principles, Ethics
- o University of Michigan // "Applied Data Science with Python" Specialization
 - Exploratory Data Analysis, Natural Language Processing, Text Mining, Social Network Analysis, Machine Learning
- o Khan Academy + Corporate Finance Institute // Various courses on Finance & Capital Markets
- o CodeCademy + DataCamp // Web Development + Data Science tracks
- o Multiple Data Science contests, hackathons, conferences and meetups

Festka s.r.o. (cycling/luxury)

Prague, Czechia

2014-2016

Director of sales & customer relations

- o Increased sales by 400% by establishing a global distribution network of 24 partners.
- o Created a sales analytics and models tools with scripts on google sheets.
- o Partnered with Pipefy.com on deployment of their kanban platform to our manufacturing processes.
- o Excelled in customer care, with a satisfaction rate superior to 98%.

Masaryk University Brno, Czechia

Post-doctorate Fellow 2012-2014

- o Continued work on own research program on higher cubical category theory and higher cubical groups.
- o Developed and taught a course on graphical calculus for postdoctoral fellows and professors
- o Gave talks in many prestigious universities, including Cambridge and Oxford.
- o Organized weekly meetings for research updates and brainstorming.

Kansas State University

Manhattan, KS, USA

2007-2012

Graduate Teaching Assistant

- o Mentored undergraduate research on Finite Double Groups.
- o Taught university-level mathematics to classes of \sim 30 young and non-traditional interdisciplinary students
- o Coordinated courses of ~200 students.

Other.....

Personal Journey
Travels

Asia/Pacific
Jan-July 2017

o Rode a 2500+ km unassisted solo cycling trip and competed in the AHBPC 2017.

- o Visited the Tibetan government to explore opportunities teaching modern sciences to buddhist Monks and Nuns.
- o Crafted Yirdakis with Djalu Gurruwiwi, elder of the Galpu clan and guardian of 60k+ years of wisdom (Arnhem Land)
- o Attempted the development of a mobile app in C# on Xamarin.

EHBA - European Hardcourt Bikepolo Association

Europe

Founding Board Member, Head

2014-2016

- o Developed the structural foundations of the organization.
- o Maintained communication with the North American and Pacific organizations.
- o Restructured EHBA around 6 poles of development, each with a 2 year mission statement before resigning.

Education

PhD, Mathematics

Fellow

Science to Data Science Program (S2DS), Pivigo

London, UK

Aug 2018

Highly Selective One of 2018's 90 PhD holders accepted in the program.

Fully immersive Onboarded in a LSE listed company for an intense 4 week project.

Team oriented Integrated a team of in-house and remote data scientists, working in an agile environment.

Impactful Delivered implementable models to the company's client.

Dept. of Mathematics, Kansas State University

Manhattan, KS, USA

June 2012

Thesis Cubical categories, TQFTs and possible new representations for the Poincare group

Supervisor Louis Crane

Award Hostinsky Outstanding GTA in Academics

Motivation Cubical categories simplify high dimensional computations in Quantum Gravity models.

CPT, Universite Aix-Marseille II

Luminy, France

MSc, Theoretical, Mathematical and Particle Physics

June 2006

Thesis 2nd Quantization of Colored Particles: Quest for the appropriate structure

Supervisor William Joyce, University of Canterbury, Christchurch, NZ

Motivation Non-associative algebras exlpain quark confinement, helping the unification of physics.

IUT de Reims Reims, France

DUT Mesures Physiques

June 2001

Specialization Materials and physico-chemical controls

Languages

FrenchEnglishJapaneseCzechGermanNativeFluentBeginnerBeginnerBeginner

Interests

Sport: Played Hardcourt Bikepolo at an international level with Prague's based "Golem". Acroyoga practitioner **Board Games**: Great way to sharpen analytic and social skills. Regular volunteer for Stronghold publishing.